<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on Data Analytics</title>
    <link>/categories/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on Data Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating welfare of borrowers by analysing Kiva dataset - part I</title>
      <link>/2018/03/21/kiva-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/21/kiva-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Kiva is an online lending platform connecting online lenders to entrepreneurs across the globe. Kiva’s mission is to connect people through lending to alleviate poverty. Kiva relies on a network of field partners to administer the loans on the ground. These field partners can be microfinance institutions, social businesses, schools or non-profit organizations. Kiva does not collect any interest on the loans it facilitates and is supported by grants, loans, and donations from the platform’s users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World bank&#39;s Poverty Prediction Competition</title>
      <link>/2018/03/14/worldbank-poverty-prediction-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/14/worldbank-poverty-prediction-competition/</guid>
      <description>Measuring poverty remains a herculean task. This is because collection of detailed data on household is expensive and at the same time consuming. Use of machine learning techniques can assist organizations such as world bank and their development partners to predict household&amp;rsquo;s poverty status more accurately and efficiently.Such accurate poverty measures provides a more solid empirical foundation of policy.
Recently the world bank conducted the Poverty-T Tests: Predicting Poverty competition, which was hosted on Driven Data platform, similar to the kaggle competition platform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>